The William Siegmann Collection, 1932-2007 IULC038 IULC038
Liberian Collections
- Research
  - Linguistics
    - "Some Terms From Liberian Speech"; Warren d'Azevedo, undated (Box 23)
    - "A Start in Gio"; Kenneth E. Griffes, 1959 (Box 23)
    - "A Start in Krahn", Isaac D. Maoh & Robert G. Grear, undated (Box 23)
    - "A Survey of Bassa Dialects"; Jana Bertkau, Joseph Gbadyo, John Duiteman & Edward Mueller, 1974 (Box 23)
    - "A Survey of Grebo Dialects in Liberia"; Frances Ingemann, undated (Box 23)
    - "A Survey of Krahn Dialects"; Frances Ingemann, undated (Box 23)
    - "A Survey of Kru Dialects"; John Duiteman, Jana Bertkau & James Laesch, 1974 (Box 23)
    - The Vai Script, Dualu Buake 1789-1853, undated (Box 23)
    - "West Atlantic: An Inventory of the Languages, Their Noun Class Systems and Consonant Alternation"; J. David Sapir, undated (Box 23)
    - "The West Atlantic Languages"; Westermann and Bryan, 1952 (Box 23)
  - Politics
    - "Annual Report of Oscar E. Greaves, Stipendiary Magistrate for Grand Bassa County for the Year August 1965 to August 1966" (Box 23)
    - "Behavioral Syndromes and Recruitment Patterns of Liberian District Commissioners, Pre 1964"; J. Gus Liebenow, 1975 (Box 23)
    - "Cultural Policy of the Republic of Liberia" (draft), 2007 (Box 23)
    - "The Eagle, The Sparrow and The Vultures: Utilitarian Origins of America's Open Door Policy Towards Libera, 1909-1933"; Larry R. Brim, 1977 (Box 23)
    - "Food, Nutrition and Economic Strategies in Development: The Need for Integration of Government Policies"; Lydia D'Alois, 1979 (Box 23)
    - "Growth, Development and All that: Thoughts on the Liberian Experience"; Elliot J. Berg, 1969 (Box 23)
    - "Hand Book or the Interior Department, 1953"; Bureau of Folkways, Mores, and Customary Laws (Box 23)
    - "Hinterland Regulations" or "An Act Approving the Administrative Regulations Proposed by the President for Governing the Hinterland Districts of the Republic", 1965 (Box 23)
    - "History of the True Whig Part, 1869-1967; Mary Fiske (Box 23)
    - "Implications of President Tolbert's Policy of Total Involvement"; Anthony J. Nimley, 1976 (Box 23)
    - "Internal Causes and Purposes of War in Europe, 1870-1956"; Arno J. Mayer, 1969 (Box 23)
    - "Landlord and Stranger Tenancy Relations in Sierra Leone"; Geoffrion, Charlesa A., 1968 (Box 23)
    - "Liberia"; J. Gus Liebenow, 1963 (Box 23)
    - "Liberia and Sierra Leone: Alternative Patterns of Central-Local Linkage"; Christopher Clapham, 1976 (Box 23)
    - "Liberia Country Development Strategy"; USAID, 1983 (Box 23)
    - "Liberia: The Dynamics of Continuity"; Thomas P. Wrubel, 1970 (Box 23)
    - "Libera: 'Mr. Doe' and the Demise of Democracy"; J. Gus Liebenow, 1984 (Box 23)
    - "The Liberian Frontier Force, 1908-1962"; Harrison Akingbade, 1978 (Box 23)
    - "Locally Empowering Rural Political Institutions in Liberia"; Svend E. Holsoe, 1994 (Box 23)
    - "Mandinka Commerical and Political Links With the Guinea-Bissau Region to the Nineteenth Century"; George E. Brooks, 1981 (Box 23)
    - "The Manipulation of Traditional Political Structures Among Coast Peoples in Western Liberia During the Nineteenth Century"; Svend E. Holsoe, 1974 (Box 23)
    - "Mass Parties and National Integration: The case of the Ivory Coast"; Aristide R. Zolberg, 1963 (Box 23)
    - "Military Affairs in Liberia, 1822-1970"; Charless Kuhlmann (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 23)
    - "Nation Building: Nigeria and Zaire"; Museum of Modern Art, 1974 (Box 23)
    - "The Nazi Edwin Barclay's Psychological Warfare in Politics (1931-1943)"; Abraham Massaquoi, 1955 (Box 23)
    - "Observation of 1997 Election - Republic of Liberia: Final Report and Evaluation"; Friends of Liberia (Box 24)
    - "Pacification Under Pressure: Government Penetration of Nimba (1910-1920)"; Martin Ford, 1987 (Box 24)
    - "Pan-Africanism and Patterns of African International Relations"; David Marvin, undated (Box 24)
    - "Political Change Among the Kpelle"; Fulton, undated (Box 24)
    - "Political Modernization & Institutional Development in Liberia"; Martin Lowenkopf, 1969 (Box 24)
    - "Political Relations Pre-AL", undated (Box 24)
    - "Political Systems and Economic Growth in Some Traditional African Societies", undated (Box 24)
    - "Politics, Privilege and Progress in Liberia: A Review Article"; Elliot J. Berg, undated (Box 24)
    - "The Praise of Mediocrity"; Lafeyette Diggs, 1993 (Box 24)
    - "The Role of Cooperatives in Tanzania"; Tessema Berga, 1967 (Box 24)
    - "The Sierra Leone Ellection of 1957"; D.J.R. Scott, 1960 (Box 24)
    - "Single-Party Systems in West Africa"; Ruth Scachter, 1961 (Box 24)
    - "Sinoe Settler Politics in Late Nineteenth Century"; Jo Sullivan, 1978 (Box 24)
    - "Some Realism About Customary Law: The West African Experience"; Gordon R. Woodman, 1966 (Box 24)
    - "Tribemen as Soldiers: on the Social and Political Psychology of the 1980 Coup D'Etat in Liberia"; Werner Korte, 1988 (Box 24)
    - "The True Whig Party of Liberia"; J. Gus Liebenow, 1963 (Box 24)
    - "Witches and Traditional Tribal Political in Tanzania"; Charless C. Kuhlmann, 1968 (Box 24)
  - Reference
    - " 1962 Population Census of Liberia", 1964 (Box 24)
    - " 1984 Population and Housing Census of Liberia: Summary Results", 1987 (Box 24)
    - Bibliographies and Catalogues (Box 24)
      - "African Dance as Human Behavior: A Selected Bibliography"; Judith Lynne Hanna, 1970 (Box 24)
      - "An Annotated Bibliography of Liberian Masks"; Edward Biggane, undated (Box 24)
      - Annotated Bibliography of Liberian Art, undated (Box 24)
      - "Annotated Bibliography of West African Textiles"; Ellen C. Werner, 1979 (Box 24)
      - "Art of the Guinea Coast: Bibliography", 1977 (Box 24)
      - "The Arts in Africa: Volume 3" (Bibliography); Janet Stanley, 1989 (Box 24)
      - Bakuba Archives, undated (Box 24)
      - Bibliography - Coastal Africa, undated (Box 24)
      - Bibliography of Liberian Art, undated (Box 24)
      - Bibliography of Liberian Art - Miscellaneous Sources and Lists, undated (Box 24)
      - "Bibliography of Southwest Mende Speakers"; Sigrid Docken Mount, 1979 (Box 24)
      - "Bibliography of the Traditional Arts & Crafts of the Kpelle, Gbandi, Loma and Mende: The Southwestern Mande-Speakers of Liberia"; Sigrid Docken Mount, 1979 (Box 24)
      - Bibliography (untitled), undated (Box 24)
      - "Bibliography - Yoruba Arts of Personal Adornment"; Sieber Seminar, 1971 (Box 24)
      - "Catalog of Liberian Government Archives"; Svend E. Holsoe, 1967 (Box 24)
      - "Catalogue of Ethnographical Specimens"; W.O. Lodman, 1906 (Box 24)
      - "A Catalogue of the Highly Important Bronzes, Ivory and Wood Carvings from the Walled City of Benin, West Africa"; Messrs. Foster, 1930 (Box 24)
      - Chicago Natural History Museum Collection Cards, undated (Box 24)
      - "Christian Imagery in African Art: The Britt Family Collection", undated (Box 24)
      - "Exhibition of Objects Illustrating the History and Condition of the Republic of Liberia" Catalogue; Chicago Historical Society, 1914 (Box 24)
      - "Films on Liberia and Her Near Neighbors"; Svend Holsoe, 1980 (Box 24)
      - "Forest and Village: Art from Liberia and Ivory Coast"; Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1988 (Box 24)
      - "A General Bibliography of the Republic of Liberia"; Warren L. d'Azevedo, 1982 (Box 24)
      - "Guide to the George War Harley Papers 1911-1975 ", 1987-2001 (Box 24)
      - "Guinea", Library of Congress Online Catalogue, undated (Box 24)
      - "Handbook of the Collection" For the New Orleans Museum of Art; Joan Caldwell & Betty N. McDermott, undated (Box 24)
      - "Index to Documents in the U.S. Department of State Diplomatic Despatches from Liberia 1852-1906 "; Gary McMillian, 1971 (Box 24)
      - "Index: Sierra Leone / Guinea / Liberia At & Culture"; Frederick Lamp, 1991 (Box 24)
      - "The Linton Collection of African Sculpture"; Yale University Art Museum, 1954 (Box 24)
      - "League of Nations Documents Related to Liberia"; C. Kuhlman, 1970 (Box 24)
      - "Masks as Agents" Peabody Museum Catalogue; George Harley, undated (Box 24)
      - National Maritime Museum Library, Greenwich, England, undated (Box 24)
      - "Personal Miniature Masks (Inventory)"; Lotte Blaustein, undated (Box 24)
      - "Report on African Materials and Activities in Some European Institutions"; Daniel McCall, 1967 (Box 24)
      - "Sources for African Studies"; Jean E. Meeh Gosebrink, 1976 (Box 24)
      - "A Study Guide for Liberia"; Howard Wolpe, undated (Box 24)
    - "Liberia: An Evaluation of Rural Research", 1971 (Box 24)
    - Maps (Box 24)
      - Aerial Navigation Map of Liberia and Sierra Leone; US Air Force, 1967 (Box 24)
      - Bellin & Barbot Maps (18th century) Copies, undated (Box 24)
      - Ethnic Groups; Svend Holsoe, undated (Box 24)
      - Europe & the Mediterranean; National Geographic, 1938 (Box 24)
      - "Geographic Map of the Zwedru Quadrangle, Liberia"; US Geological Survey & Liberian Ministry of Lands and Mines, 1972 (Box 24)
      - "Geographic Map of the Sanokole Quadrangle, Liberia"; US Geological Survey & Liberian Ministry of Lands and Mines, 1973 (Box 24)
      - Grebo Maps, undated (Box 24)
      - Guinea ( 1730-1734), undated (Box 24)
      - Language Group Maps, undated (Box 24)
      - Liberia - Ashmun's Maps, undated (Box 24)
      - Liberia Central Province, undated (Box 25)
      - Liberia (Firestone, undated (Box 25)
      - Liberia Geographic Maps, 1972 (Box 25)
      - Liberia Historical Maps, undated (Box 25)
      - Liberia - Individual Settlements ( 1835), undated (Box 25)
      - Liberia - Miscellaneous,, undated, 1946-1969 (Box 25)
      - Lynch Reports Maps, undated (Box 25)
      - Maps & Plates from Thomas Astley, undated (Box 25)
      - Michelin, Africa, 1969 (Box 25)
      - Mobil, Liberia, 1970 (Box 25)
      - Monrovia,, undated, 1960-1962 (Box 25)
      - "Planimetric Map of Liberia", 1957 (Box 25)
      - "Region du Cavally", undated (Box 25)
      - Research Pack, 1972 (Box 25)
      - Sierra Leone & Ivory Coast, 1977 (Box 25)
      - States of the Guinea Forest, undated (Box 25)
      - "Transportation Map of Liberia", 1972bundoo (Box 25)
    - Maps & Charts; Liberian Information Service Visual Aid Center, undated (Box 25)
    - "Poisonous Snakes of Liberia"; U.S. Navy (Box 25)
  - Religion
    - "The 50th Anniversary of the Holy Cross Mission at Bolahun"; John Gay, 1972 (Box 25)
    - "Afro-American Religions: Traditions and Transformations"; Erika E. Bourguignon, undated (Box 25)
    - "A Challenge for the Eighties: The Future of Liberian Society"; Michael Francis & Boniface Nyema Daileh, 1979 (Box 25)
    - "Changing Liberia: A Challenge to the Christian"; John P. Mitchell, 1959 (Box 25)
    - "The Church Looks at the Devil Bush"; G. Gordon Parker (Box 25)
    - "The Divine Kingship of the Aga Khan: A Study of Theocracy in East Africa"; H.S. Morris, 1958 (Box 25)
    - "Ere: The Essence of the Image in Yoruba Religious Sculptures"; Cornelius Oyoleke Adepegba, 1981 (Box 25)
    - "An Historical Sketch of the Africa Mission"; Protestant Episcopal Church, undated (Box 25)
    - "The History of Islam in Liberia: Mande Pioneers on the Frontiers of Faith"; Humphrey J. Fisher, 1968 (Box 25)
    - "The Invisible Mothers: Female Power in Yoruba Iconography"; Hans Witte, 1985 (Box 25)
    - "Kraisti a Poi Nyo or Christ Our Savior" ( 1843), undated (Box 25)
    - "Kru Religious Concepts - Ky and Nyeswa"; Thomas E. Hayden, 1977 (Box 25)
    - "Liberia: From Outpost to Church"; Jeannie Willis, 1972 (Box 25)
    - "Liberian Materials in the Christian Advocate", undated (Box 25)
      A 19th century bibliography
    - "Methodist Missionaries in Liberia", 1964 (Box 25)
    - "Mission Groups in Liberia", undated (Box 25)
    - "The New Religions of Africa"; Jules-Rosette Benetta, 1979 (Box 25)
    - "A Policy of Baptizing Polygynists Evaluated"; Gerald Currens (Box 25)
    - "The Pope Speaks - Liberia"; Pius XII, 1956 (Box 25)
    - "Religion: Three Systems of Belief", undated (Box 25)
    - "The Religious Basis for Traditional Authority in Tribal Liberia"; Robert Luneberg, undated (Box 25)
    - "A Short History of the Protestant Episcopal Missino in Grand Bassa" ( 1905 ); R.F. Cooper, undated (Box 25)
    - "The Sierra Leone Bulletin of Religon", 1959 (Box 25)
    - "The Spirits and their Terrestrial Personification, as the Basic Concept in the Religion of the Dan"; Hans Himmelheber, 1964 (Box 25)
    - "Stratification and Religious Affiliation in a Liberian Coastal Town"; Charles Justice, 1978 (Box 25)
  - Secret Societies
    - "The Adaptive Powers of Poro Arts"; Beryl Bellman, 1991 (Box 25)
    - "Aspects of the Poro in Sierra Leone and Liberia"; Thomas Seligman, 1981 (Box 25)
    - "The Beauty of the Sowo - Spirit of the Mende Women's Secret Society"; Frank A. Dubinskas, 1972-1979 (Box 25)
    - "The Bundu Bush Initiation Rite"; Gerius Pearce, undated (Box 25)
    - Circumcision and Cliterodectomy, undated (Box 25)
    - "The Devil Bush of the Golas: A West African Secret Society That Dominates Tribal Life"; John W. Vandercook, 1927 (Box 25)
    - "The Devil Bush of West Africa" (1896); Rev C.C. Penick, undated (Box 25)
    - "Devilman's Jungle"; Gustaf Bolinder, 1954 (Box 25)
    - "Dynamique de la Societies Ouobe"; Girard, 1978 (Box 25)
    - " 'Everywoman' and the 'Super-Woman' "; D Frank Anthony Dubinskas, 1976 (Box 25)
    - "Features of Secrecy Among the Fala Kpelle"; Beryl Bellman, 1969 (Box 25)
    - "Fundamentals of Gola Poro and Sande"; Warren d'Azevedo, undated (Box 25)
    - "Girls Initiation Among the Mende" Art and Photography Exhibit, 1979 (Box 25)
    - "Gola Poro and Sande: Primal Tasks in Social Custodianship"; Warren d'Azevedo, 1980 (Box 25)
    - "The Gree-Gree Bush (Initiation Of Youth) Among the Golah Negroes, Liberia" ( 1911 ); P. Jean Marie Ceston, undated (Box 25)
    - "The Influence of Islam on Poro and Sande in Western Liberia"; S. Jangaba M. Johnson, undated (Box 25)
    - "Initiation and the Bull-Roarer", undated (Box 25)
    - "The Initiation of Temne Poro Officials"; Vernon R. Dorjahn, 1961 (Box 25)
    - Liberian Poro; Kuhlman, C., undated (Box 25)
    - "Masking in Mende Sande Society Initiation Rituals"; Ruth B. Phillips, 1978 (Box 25)
    - "Masks, Societies, and Secrecy Among the Fala Kpelle"; Beryl Bellman, 1978 (Box 25)
    - "Notes on the Vai Sande Society in Liberia"; Svend Holsoe, 1979-0992 (Box 26)
    - "One Man's Sande: Roger Dorsinville's 'L'Homme Derriere l'arbre: un Haitien au Liberia', a Photographic Initiation"; George Lang, 1995 (Box 26)
    - Political Function of the Poro; Geffrion, undated (Box 26)
    - "The Political Structures and Functions of Poro in Kpelle Society"; Fulton, Richard M., 1972 (Box 26)
    - "The Poro as a System of Judicial Administration in Northwestern Liberia: Its Intraclan and Interclan Functions"; Richard P. Fahey, 1971 (Box 26)
    - "Poro Communications (West Africa): A Spiritual Channel Where Men are the Means of Transmission"; Ojo Arewa & Everett E. Hale, 1975 (Box 26)
    - "Poro Masks: A Few Comments on Masks as an Agent of Social Control by Dr. G.W. Harley"; P. Jan Vandenhoute (Box 26)
    - "The Poro Secret Society: A Study of its Socialisation, Political and Social Control Functions Among the Mano of Liberia"; Patrick J. Harrington, 1973 (Box 26)
    - "The Poro Society as an Arbiter of Culture"; K.L. Little, 1948 (Box 26)
    - "The Poro Society: The Building of the Poro House and Making of the Image"; F.W. Misgeod II, undated (Box 26)
    - "The Poro Values and Courtroom Procedures in a Kpelle Chiefdom"; James L. Gibbs, Jr., undated (Box 26)
    - "A Revelation of the Secret Orders of Western Africa" ( 1886 ); J. Cole Augustus, undated (Box 26)
    - "The Sande: A Socio-Cultural Organization in the Mende Community of Sierra Leone", J.V.O. Richards, 1974 (Box 26)
    - "The Sande and Some of the Forces That Inspired Its Creation or Adoption With Some References to the Poro"; J.V.O. Richards, 1973 (Box 26)
    - "The Sande Mask"; J.V.Olufemi Richards, 1974 (Box 26)
    - "Secret Societies and Fetishism in Sierra Leone" ( 1907 ); A.R. Wright, undated (Box 26)
    - "Secret Societies in Liberia" ( 1922 ); Hans Schomburgk, undated (Box 26)
    - Secret Societies of Sierra Leone (1919); Warren, undated (Box 26)
    - Secret Societies - The Poro ( 1901 ); T.J. Alldrige, undated (Box 26)
    - "The Secret Society"; Paul Germann, undated (Box 26)
    - "Secret Society Rites of Women in Liberia Bantu Order"; Hans Schomburgk, 1967 (Box 26)
    - "Similarities and Differences in Male and Female Secret Societies Among the Bafodea Limba of Northern Sierra Leone"; Simon Ottenberg, 1981 (Box 26)
    - "Social and Symbolic Values of Feminine Kne Initiation Among the Guro of the Ivory Coast"; Ariane Deluz, 1987 (Box 26)
    - "Status Mobility of 'Poro' Masks: Bridging the Discrepancy Between Stylistic and Functional Typologies"; Kurt R. Moore, 1979 (Box 26)
    - "Stratification and Sande Politics"; Caroline H. Bledsoe, 1980 (Box 26)
    - "Structural Aspects of a West African Society"; M.C. Jerdrej, 1976 (Box 26)
    - "Symbolism in Wan Female Initiation"; Philip Ravenhill, 1978 (Box 26)
    - "The Vai Women's Society Mask"; Ruth B. Phillips, 1972 (Box 26)
    - "West African Bundoo" ( 1905 ); L.F. Smith, undated (Box 26)
    - "The Women's Bundu Society Mask of The Mende in Sierra Leone"; Annette K. Grob, 1975 (Box 26)
  - Subject Files
    - African Traditional Thought Course Notes, undated (Box 26)
    - American Museum of Natural History Anthropology Collections, 2005 (Box 26)
    - Guidelines for the Drafting of Land Tenure Decree, 1987 (Box 26)
    - Holsoe Field Notes-Zwedru, 1986 (Box 26)
    - "Land and Power in Liberia"; Leon Weintraub, 1970 (Box 26)
    - "Liberia: An Evaluation of Rural Research"; Richard M. Fulton, ed, 1971 (Box 26)
    - "The Liberian Merchant Flag, 1949-1977"; Rodney Carlisle (Box 26)
    - The Making of Liberia's Flag, undated (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 26)
    - "Patterns of Authority in West Africa"; Paula Brown, 1951 (Box 26)
    - "A Primitive Gyroscope in Liberia"; G.N. Collins, undated (Box 26)
    - Robertsport Notes, undated (Box 26)
    - "Rubber-Cushioned Liberia"; Henry S. Villard, 1948 (Box 26)
    - Second African Presence, undated (Box 26)
    - "Survey of Psychological Research in Liberia"; Orin James Martin, 1976 (Box 26)
    - "The Wangara, An Old Soninke Diaspora in West Africa?"; Andreas W. Massing, 1999 (Box 26)
    - West Africa 15th-19th Century Syllabus (George Brooks), 1979 (Box 26)
  - Travel
    - "Adventures with the Krus in West Africa"; Walter B. and Maude Williams, 1955 (Box 26)
    - "Central Africa" ( 1849 ); Thomas J. Bowen, undated (Box 26)
    - "A Description of the Coasts of North and South Guinea; and of Ethiopia Inferior, vulgarly Angola: Being a New and Accurate Account of the Western Maritime Countries of Africa" ( 1732 ); James Barbot, undated (Box 26)
    - "The English Voyages" ( 1555 ); William Towerson, undated (Box 26)
    - "Esmeraldo de Situ Orbis" (English, 1505 ); Duarte Pacheco Pareira, undated (Box 26)
    - "From Cape Mount and the Whole Grain Coast" ( 1694 ); normal="Gröben, Otto Friedrich von der, 1657-1728 "source="lcnaf">Otto Friedrich von der Groben, undated (Box 26)
    - "The Hinterland of Cape Palmas" ( 1903 ), undated (Box 26)
    - "Hostains-d'Ollone"; Monni Adams, 1994 (Box 26)
    - "I Found Africa"; Van Nes Allen, 1939 (Box 26)
    - "Introducing 'Descriptions and Historical Account of the Golden Kingdom of Guinea' by Pieter de Marees"; J.B. Ammissah, 1969 (Box 26)
    - "Journal of a Journey by J.B. Cates & Others in Feby March & April 1819", 1991 (Box 26)
      Paper print made by Warren d'Azevedo
    - "Journal of a voyage from Boston to the west coast of Africa" ( 1852 ); Joshua A. Carnes, undated (Box 26)
    - "A Journal of a Voyage Made in the Hannibal of London, Ann. 1693, 1694, From England, to Cape's Monseradoe, in Africa, And Thence Along the Coast of Guiney to Whidaw, the Island of St. Thomas, An So Forward to Barbadoes: With a Cursory Account of the County, the People, Their Manners, Forts, Trade, &c " ( 1732 ); Phillips, Thomas, undated (Box 26)
    - "The Kru Coast, Cape Palmas, and the Niger" ( 1861); Durrant, William, undated (Box 26)
    - "Land of Hope: Reminiscences of Liberia and Cape Palmas, with Incidents of the Voyage" ( 1852 ); Hoyt, William B., undated (Box 26)
    - "Liberian Odyssey: By Hammock and Surfboat"; F.A. Price, 1954 (Box 26)
    - "Memoirs of Rev. J. L. Wilson" ( 1895); C. DuBose Hampden, undated (Box 26)
    - "Memoirs of Rev. J. L. Wilson" ( 1848); Rebecca B. Medberry, undated (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous Travel, undated (Box 26)
    - "Narrative of the Expedition Despatched to Musah-Du, Capital of the Western Mandindas" ( 1874); Benjamin Anderson, undated (Box 26)
    - "Negro-Land"; Ogilby, undated (Box 26)
    - "On Board the Duke of Argyle at Rio Junque" ( 1753); John Newton, undated (Box 26)
    - "On Liberia", undated (Box 26)
    - "The River of the Palms, and many others" ( 1463); Alvise Cadamosto, undated (Box 26)
    - "Roads and Trails in Liberia"; G.W. Harley, 1939 (Box 26)
    - "The Sacred Forest"; Nicolas Mosley, 1958 (Box 26)
    - "The Second Voyage to Guinea" ( 1553); John Lok, undated (Box 26)
    - "Ship James log" ( 1675), undated (Box 26)
    - "A Tour in the Liberian Hinterland"; Capt. Braithwaite Wallis, undated (Box 26)
    - "Tourism"; Ivory Coast Embassy, undated (Box 26)
    - "A Transformed Colony" ( 1910); T.J. Aldridge, undated (Box 26)
    - "Travels in Africa" ( 1878); Silvester Golbery, undated (Box 26)
    - "A Voyage to Guinea" ( 1669; Villault, undated (Box 26)
    - "Voyages and Travels to the West Coast of Africa Before 1800"; Bruce Mouser, 1966 (Box 26)
    - "The Western Coast - Wastrom's Settlement", undated (Box 26)
- Subject Files
  Includes 4 boxes of unprocessed materials not listed
  - African Studies Program, Indiana University - J. Gus Liebenow, 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Andreas Massing
    - Annotated Bibliography of Liberian Art, undated (Box 28)
    - Field Museum of Natural History,, undated, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Frobenius Institute, 1970 (Box 28)
    - Goteborg Ethnografiska Museum, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 28)
    - National Museum of Natural History,, undated, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Neprajzi Museum,, undated, 1972 (Box 28)
    - UCLA,, undated, 1972 (Box 28)
  - "Background Information for University Planning", 1974 (Box 28)
  - Civil War
    - Africa Faith and Justice Network, 1990 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1985-1997 (Box 28)
    - "The Devil They Know"; Jon Lee Anderson, 1998 (Box 28)
    - "Easy Prey: Child Soldiers in Liberia"; Human Rights Watch, 1994 (Box 28)
    - "History of Liberian Civil War, 1989-1993"; K. George (Box 28)
    - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, 1990-1991 (Box 28)
    - Liberia Watch, undated, 1990-1993 (Box 28)
    - "Liberian Diaspora", 1991 (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1985-2002 (Box 28)
    - News Articles, undated, 1983-2007 (Box 28)
    - Relief Organizations, undated, 1990-1993 (Box 28)
    - "Violence Against Women During The Liberian Civil Conflict"; Shana Swiss et al, 1993 (Box 28)
  - Conferences and Meetings
    - Liberia Archives Symposium, 2008 (Box 28)
    - Liberian Social Science Research 3rd Annual Conference, 1971 (Box 28)
      3 folders
    - Liberian Studies Association 2nd Annual Conference, 1970 (Box 28)
    - Liberian Studies Association 4th Annual Conference, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Liberian Studies Association 9th Annual Conference, 1977 (Box 28)
    - Liberian Studies Association 14th Annual Conference, 1982 (Box 28)